Paetel, Karl O.; Papers ger072
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Materials Collections, 1925-1975; 7
  - Subject Files on Various Topics, Undated; 7.2
    - Civil rights issues / Black issues., Undated (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Communism, Germany., Undated (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Communism, U.S., Undated (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Confiscated property., Undated (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Congo., Undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Conservatism, Right-wing politics., Undated (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Council for a Democratic Germany., Undated (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Cuban crisis, 1962. (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - DDR / East Germany., Undated (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Democratic Socialists., Undated (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Demokratischer Kulturbund Deutschlands., Undated (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Deutsche Friedensgesellschaft., Undated (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Deutsche Friedens-Union., Undated (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Deutsche Reichs-Partei (DRP)., Undated (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Deutsche Union / Deutsche Gemeinschaft., Undated (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Drugs., Undated (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Foreign Press Association. Membership directories, 1955-1972. (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - Freikorps., Undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - German General Staff Corps., Undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Germany. Concentration Camps., Undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Germany during World War II, 1941-1945. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Germany, 1945., Undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Germany, Occupation of., Undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Germany, peace aims., Undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Germany, post-1945., Undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Germany, remilitarization., Undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Germany, reunification., Undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Gestapo / SS / SD (Sicherheitsdienst)., Undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Goethe House (Goethe-Haus), New York., Undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Greenwich Village, New York City., Undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Gypsies., Undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Handbills., Undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Hitler, Adolf., Undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Hitler, Adolf. Photos., Undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Hitler's military power / Hitler's generals., Undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Holocaust., Undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Homosexuals., Undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC)., Undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Hungary., Undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Hutterites (Hutterer)., Undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Israel., Undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Japan., Undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Jewish topics., Undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - John Birch Society., Undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Articles in German., Undated (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Articles in English (1)., Undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Articles in English (2)., Undated (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Magazine articles, special issues (1)., Undated (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Magazine articles, special issues (2)., Undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Magazine articles, special issues (3)., Undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald. Photographs., Undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Kommunistische Partei Deutschland (KPD)., Undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Korea., Undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Ku Klux Klan., Undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Guaranteed annual wage (Jahreslohn)., Undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Labor unions (Gewerkschaften). Articles in English, primarily 1954. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Labor unions (Gewerkschaften). Articles in English, 1955+. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Labor unions (Gewerkschaften). Articles in German., Undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Landsberg prison., Undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - League for Mutual Aid., Undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Leftists., Undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Literature, European., Undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Literature, German exile (Deutsche Exilliteratur)., Undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Literature, German – Nazi., Undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Literature, German post-1945. (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Literature, U.S., Undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Literature and theater, black., Undated (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Mafia., Undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Museum of Modern Art., Undated (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - NAACP., Undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - National bolshevism (Nationalbolschewismus), 1926-1933. (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - National bolshevism (Nationalbolschewismsu), later articles., Undated (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - National socialism / Nazis., Undated (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Nationalkomittee Freies Deutschland / Free Germany Committee. Articles in German., Undated (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Nationalkomittee Freies Deutschland / Free Germany Committee. Articles in English., Undated (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Nazi trials., Undated (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Neofaschismus / Neo-Nazis (1)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Neofaschismus / Neo-Nazis (2)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Neofaschismus. Sammlung zur Tat (SzT)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - New Left (1960s)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Office of Jewish Information. News releases., Undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Oppo-Verlag., Undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Peace Corps., Undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - P.E.N. Club., Undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Press / News media., Undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Protestants., Undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Publisher's advertisements., Undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Puerto Rico / Puerto Ricans., Undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Radical Youth. Clippings., Undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Radical Youth. Publications, A-B., Undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Radical Youth. Publications, D-K., Undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Radical Youth. Publications, M-R., Undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Radical Youth. Publications, S-Z., Undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Radical Youth. Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), publications., Undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Rapallo., Undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Refugees / Expellees (1)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Refugees / Expellees (2)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Refugees / Expellees (3)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Refugees / Expellees (4)., Undated (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Refugees / Expellees (5)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Refugees / Expellees (6)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Refugees / Expellees. Miscellaneous publications (1)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Rufugees / Expellees. Miscellaneous publications (2)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Refugees / Expellees. Newsletters., Undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Refugees / Expellees. Schleswig-Holstein., Undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Refugees / Expellees. U.S. Zone., Undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Right-to-work laws., Undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Social Security system, U.S., Undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - .Socialism, U.S., Undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Soviet Union., Undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Sozialistische Deutsche Friedensfront., Undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Sozialistische Einheitspartei (SED)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Sozialistische Partei Deutschland (SPD)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Sozialistische Reichspartei (SRP). Neofaschismus., Undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Spiegel-affair, 1962. (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Stätte der Begegnung., Undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Stalinism., Undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Sturmabteilung (SA)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Sudetenland / Sudetendeutsch., Undated (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Tito / Titoism., Undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - U.S. General articles., Undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - U.S. politics, general., Undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Vietnam / Anti-war., Undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Vietnam. March on Washington, April 24, 1969., 1969 April 24 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Waffen-SS., Undated (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Weisses Ren (convent)., Undated (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Wiedergutmachung., Undated (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Women's Rights., Undated (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Woodstock, New York., Undated (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - World War II. General articles., Undated (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - World War II, German military., Undated (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Youth, issues and problems, post-1945., Undated (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - Heinz Gollong Scrapbook Collection, 1925-1932; 7.3
    The scrapbooks were compiled by Heinz Gollong and contain materials pertaining to the German youth group, Jungsturm, and other youth movement issues.
    - Scrapbook 1: Jungsturm materials, 1925-1927, including issues of: Jungflieger (No. 1-6/7, 1926), 1926 November 1-1926 November 7 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Der Zwiespruch (incomplete issues), Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Die Kommenden (I, No. 19), Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Nachrichtenblatt des Bundes Jungdeutschland und des deutschen Jungmädchendienstes (I, No. 3, 5, II, No. 1), Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Jungsturm (XXI, No. 1-12), Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - clippings of articles concerning the youth group Jungsturm (1925-1927) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook 2: Jungsturm materials 1928, including issues of Jungsturm (XXII, No. 1-12), Undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Die Kommenden (III, No. 13, 15-18, Sondernummer), Undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - clippings and single periodical issues., Undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook 3: Jungsturm materials, 1929, including issues of Jungsturm (XXIII, No. 1-12) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - several periodicals issues from 1911-1916 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - clippings by Gollong and others concerning Jungsturm and other youth groups, Undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - periodical issues from 1929 articles pertaining to Jungsturm. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook 4: 1929-1930. Issues of Die Kommenden (IV [1929], No. 34, 48, 52 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - V [1930], No. 2-4, 7, 11-14, 16, 19, 21, 26, 27, 29, 32, 35, 37, 42, 43); issues of Jungsturm (XXIV [1930], No. 1, 2, 5, 10) (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - clippings by Heinz Gollong; periodical issues and clippings pertaining to youth movement., Undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook 5: 1929-1930. Issues of Die Kommenden (IV [1929], No. 37, 48 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - V [1930], No. 1, 9, 11, 12, 15-17, 19, 20, 22-28, 32, 35, 36, 38, 39); clippings by Heinz Gollong, Werner Laß and others., Undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook 6: 1931. Issues of Die Kommenden (VI [1931], No. 4, 5, 8-11, 13-16, 18-20, 22, 24, 27, 29, 32-34, 37, 50, 51/52) (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - clippings by Heinz Gollong and others., Undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook 7: 1931-1932. Issues of Die Kommenden (VII [1932], No. 1, 4, 6, 9, 11, 13, 14, 17, 19, 20, 22, 23/24, 26-28, 38) (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - issues of Gegner (I [1931], No. 7 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - II [1932], 5 May, 20 May, 10 June, June Sondernummer (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - III [1932], No. 1 /2-5/6, 9/10) (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - clippings by Heinz Gollong, Undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - clippings and individual periodical issues., Undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook 8: 1933-1936, including issues of Wille zum Reich (1934-1936) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Reichsschrifttumskammer; Der Schriftsteller (1934, No. 1-10) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - later Der deutsche Schriftsteller (II [1937], No. 2) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Reichspressekammer; clippings of articles by Heinz Gollong and others., Undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Ernst Jnger Collection, 1925-1972; 7.4
    - Manuscripts by Jnger, 1940-1945; 7.4.1
      - Am Sarazenenturm. T. 95p., with handwritten note to Paetel., Undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - "Drei Silben." Poem, dated 1940. T. 1p. (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - "Der Friede. Ein Wort an die Jugend Europas. Ein Wort an die Jugend der Welt." T., undated. ii, 23p.; later version, dated 4. April 1945. T. 26p.; another version, dated Ende September / Anfang Oktober 1945. T.cc. 34p., 1945 April-1945 October (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - "Geleitwort," to Hans Speidel. Invasion 1944. Ein Beitrag zu Rommels und des Reiches Schicksal. T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Sanduhren T. 114p., with handwritten note to Paetel., Undated (Box 37, Folder 4a)
      - Strahlungen. "Einleitung." T.cc. 12p. Another copy. T.cc. 7p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - "Vorwort des Herausgebers," to Friedrich Georg Jünger. Aufmarsch des Nationalismus. T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - "Vorwort des Herausgebers," to Ernst Schauwecker. Der feurige Welt. T.cc. 2 copies, 3p. ea., Undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Publications by Jnger (Clippings), 1925-1972; 7.4.2
      This subseries consists primarily of clippings of articles from periodicals and includes numerous excerpts from the full-length novels of Jnger, as well as clippings of essayistic writings.
      - Das abenteuerliche Herz – excerpts: "Der schwarze Sey"; "Figuren und Capriccios.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Excerpts from novels:Am Kieselstrand – excerpts: "Die Sehnsucht nach Erlösung.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Excerpts from novels:Am Sarazenenturm – excerpts: "Irgend- und nirgendwo.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Excerpts from novels:An der Zeitmauer – excerpts: "Das Glück"; "Der Siegeszug der Astrologie ist ein revolutionäres Zeichen"; "Experiment, Fehlleistung und Freiheit.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Excerpts from novels:Annäherungen – Drogen und Rausch – excerpt: "Früher Einstieg mit Extractum Cannabis.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Excerpts from novels:Auf den Marmorklippen – excerpts, including "Nachschrift.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - Excerpts from novels:Ein Inselfrühling – excerpts., Undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Excerpts from novels:Der Friede! "Als Manuskript gedruckt." Contains a handwritten note "Illegale Ausgabe der Friedensschrift.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - Excerpts from novels:Der Friede! – excerpts; French version "La paix.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - Excerpts from novels:Gläserne Bienen – excerpts: "Mit den Wölfen muß man helfen.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - Excerpts from novels:Der gordische Knoten – excerpts: "Ost und West.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
      - Excerpts from novels:Heliopolis – excerpts: "Gespräch auf dem Pagos"; "Zwei Episoden"; "Lucius und Melitta.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - Excerpts from novels:Jahre der Okkupation – excerpts: "Erinnerungen an die Besatzungszeit"; "Kriege verändern auf jeden Fall"; "Zwei Journalisten aus USA"; "'Doch im Innern ist's getan'.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 20)
      - Excerpts from novels:Myrdun – excerpt: "Celsus, der Arzt oder Die natürliche Heilung.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 21)
      - Excerpts from novels:Sand-Flöhen – excerpt., Undated (Box 37, Folder 22)
      - Excerpts from novels:Sanduhrbuch – excerpts: "Das Glas der Zeit"; "'Was kehrt dem wieder?'"; "Bewegung und Ruhe"; "Die andere Seite der Uhrenwelt.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
      - Excerpts from novels:Sgraffiti – excerpts: "Das Zahlen-Kaleidoskop"; "Mensch zwischen Affe und Vogel"; "Wüste und Meere"; excerpt in French., Undated (Box 37, Folder 24)
      - Strahlungen – excerpts: "Meditation zu Sylvester 1944"; "Der letzte Tage des Krieges"; "Kniébolo"; "Pariser Perspektiven"; "Die Folgen der Ausrottung"; "Aufzeichnungen aus Paris und dem Osten"; "Fragments du Journal" (French); "Execution d'un deserte (Box 37, Folder 25-26)
      - Excerpts from novels:Sturm – bound photocopies of serialization., Undated (Box 37, Folder 27)
      - Excerpts from novels:Subtile Jagden – excerpt: "Rückblick.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 28)
      - Excerpts from novels:Typus, Name, Gestalt – excerpt: "Das Wort auf der Waage.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 29)
      - Excerpts from novels:Über die Linie – excerpts: "Wo ist noch Freiheit?"; "Wir zwischen den Mächten"; "Passage de la ligne" (French)., Undated (Box 37, Folder 30)
      - Excerpts from novels:Der Waldgang – excerpts: "Des Leviathans Partner"; " Die entschiedene Minderheit"; "Der Mensch im uranischen Zeitalter"; "Eigenschaften des Waldgangers.", Undated (Box 37, Folder 31)
      - Essayistic:Die Standarte. Photocopies of articles published, 1925-1926: "Unsere Politiker"; "Wesen des Frontsoldatentums"; "Abgrenzung und Verbindung"; "Der Frontsoldat und die Wilhelminische Zeit"; "Der Krieg als äußeres Erlebnis"; "Die Materialschlacht"; "Der Krieg als inneres Erlebnis"; "Die Revolution"; "Die Methode der Revolution"; "Die Reaktion"; "Die Tradition"; "Der Pazifismus"; "Der Internationalismus"; "Der Frontsoldat und die innere Politik"; "Blut und Intellekt"; "Die Maschine"; "Schluß"; "Zum Jahre. Nationalisten!"; "Zentrale Leitung?" (Box 37, Folder 32)
      - Essayistic:Die Standarte. Edited by Ernst Jünger, Helmut Franke, Franz Schauwecker, Wilhelm Kleinau. Individual issues, 1926-1927. (Box 37, Folder 33)
      - Essayistic:Arminius. Photocopies of articles published, 1926-1927: "Der jungdeutsche Kritikaster"; "Kasernenhöfe der Idee"; "Der Sonderrecht des Nationalismus"; "Die antinationalen Mächte"; "Totem"; "Reichswehr und Propaganda." (Box 37, Folder 34)
      - Essayistic:Arminius. Edited by Helmut Franke, in collaboration with Ernst Jünger and Wilhelm Weiss. Individual issues, 1926-1927. (Box 37, Folder 35)
      - Essayistic:Vormarsch. Photocopies of articles published, 1927-1929: "Zum Geleit"; "Die Opfer"; "Die Blindgänger des großen Krieges"; "Zum Jahreswechsel"; "Die Reichswehr"; "Arbeiter und Soldaten des 20. Jahrhunderts"; "Alfonso de Contreras"; "Nation und Luftfahrt"; "Der Nationalismus der Tat"; "Aus meinem Skizzenbuch"; "Der unsichbare Kern." (Box 37, Folder 36)
      - Essayistic:Widerstand. Photocopies of articles published, 1927-1933: "Vom Geiste"; "Die Lebenden und die Toten"; "Die andere Seite"; "Revolution um Karl Marx"; "Der Wille zur Gestalt"; "Reinheit der Mittel"; "Schlußwort zu einem Aufsatz"; "Trotzkis Erinnerungen"; "Über die Gefahr"; "Ein neuer Bericht aus dem Lande der Planwirtschaft." (Box 37, Folder 37)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1926. Photocopies: "Großstadt und Land." (Box 37, Folder 38)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1928. Photocopies: "Drei Soldaten." (Box 37, Folder 39)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1929. Photocopies: "Das sibirische Tagebuch"; "Gedanken eines Soldaten"; "Deutsche Bücher"; "Aus der untersten Zelle"; "'Nationalismus' und Nationalismus." (Box 37, Folder 40)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1930. Photocopies: "Die Geächteten"; "Die Arbeits-Mobilmachung"; "Über Nationalismus und Judenfrage"; "Das Unzerstörbare." (Box 37, Folder 41)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1933: "Untergang oder neue Ordnung?" (Box 37, Folder 42)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1947: "Pour la Jeunesse de l'Europe et du monde." (Box 37, Folder 43)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1948: "Atlantische Fahrt." (Box 37, Folder 44)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1949: "Die Stimme von Ernst Jünger." (Box 37, Folder 45)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1950: "Geier im Hafen von Para"; "Av Leif Woerenskjold"; "Die Eberjagd." (Box 37, Folder 46)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1951: "Die leere Gebärde. Ernst Jüngers Gedanken über die Kirche / Neue Zuwendung zum Sein." (Box 37, Folder 47)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1952: "Die Inseln"; "Polarisations." (Box 37, Folder 48)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1953: "Europa"; "Kleine Mitteilungen"; "Bilderfülle am Äquator. Brasilien-Reisebericht"; "Unser Leben." (Box 37, Folder 49)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1954: "Zeitglas und Atomuhr"; "Schöne Chao-chun"; "Blick auf Uhren"; "La part à Dieu." (Box 37, Folder 50)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1956: "Ein Sonntag Vormittag in Paris"; "Ernst Jüngers Bremer Preisdank. Zur Erinnerung an die Feier im Rathaus"; "Das Vaterland als Schicksalskostüm"; "Bilderfülle am Äquator." (Box 37, Folder 51)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1957: "Bilder"; "Some Reflections" (Box 37, Folder 52)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1958: "Standflächen"; "Die Thunfischschlacht." (Box 37, Folder 53)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1959: "Über den Schmerz"; "November." (Box 37, Folder 54)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1960: "Angeregt durch ein Bilderbuch"; "Vierblätter." (Box 37, Folder 55)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1961: "Weihnachten im zwanzigsten Jahrhundert." (Box 37, Folder 56)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1962: "Am Rande der Steppe"; "Pariser Reisetraum." (Box 37, Folder 57)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1963: "Von Zeit zu Zeit wechseln die Landschaften." (Box 37, Folder 58)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1965: "Die ernste Sache." (Box 37, Folder 59)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1967: "Argus hat hundert Augen. Ein Käfersammler beginnt seine Jagden"; "Das tanzende Holz. Tierische Gesellen im Studio." (Box 37, Folder 60)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1968: "Krieg und Grenzen sind veraltet." (Box 37, Folder 61)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1969: "Zwei Besuche. In memoriam Jean Schlumberger." (Box 37, Folder 62)
      - Essayistic:Essays, 1972: "Auf dem Terrassengestade. Reiseskizzen aus Formosa"; "Was Herr Seldte sagen sollte..." (Box 37, Folder 63)
      - Essayistic:Essays, undated. 5 items. (Box 37, Folder 64)
    - Secondary Literature and Reviews, 1928-1975; 7.4.3
      This section contains manuscripts of articles on Jnger, as well as clippings of published articles about Jnger in general, as well as reviews of individual works.
      - Manuscripts: Anon. "Ernst Jünger: Pressestimmen aus dem Jahre 1946." T. with h. corr. 27p. (Box 37, Folder 65)
      - Manuscripts:Anon. "Die Politik im Leben Ernst Jüngers." T. with numerous corr. 258p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 66)
      - Manuscripts:Andres, Stefan. "Eine halblaute Frage." T.cc. 4p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 67)
      - Manuscripts:Dahler, Ilse. "Untersuchungen zu Sprache und Stil Ernst Jüngers. Diss. Giessen 1944. T.cc. 135p. (Box 37, Folder 68)
      - Manuscripts:des Coudres, Hans Peter. "Ernst Jünger (Weg und Werk)." Dated 1951. T.cc. 10p. (Box 37, Folder 69)
      - Manuscripts:Germain, André. "Ernst Jünger." T.cc. 5p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 70)
      - Manuscripts:Greiner, Götz. "Ernst-Jünger-Dissertationen." Dated December 1957. T.cc.7p., 1957 December (Box 37, Folder 71)
      - Manuscripts:Hennig, Wolfgang. "Leben in sokratischem Geist. Der Weg Ernst Jüngers im Bekenntnis seiner Schriften." T.cc. 5p., Undated (Box 37, Folder 72)
      - Heyer, G. R. "Ernst Jünger in seiner Bedeutung für die Seelenheilkunde." Mimeo. 41p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Klipstein, Christian. "Ernst Jünger und sein Werk im Lichte der Kritik." T.cc. 5p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Klipstein, Editha. "Der geistige Mut." Dated 21.10.1946. T.cc. with h. corr. 6p. Another version. T.cc. 7p., 1946 October 21 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Kraus, Fritz. "Gespräch über Ernst Jüngers Schrift 'Über die Linie'." Radio text. T.cc. 12p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Kreuter, Irmgard. "Mythos und Intellekt im Weltverständnis Ernst Jüngers." T.cc. viii, 84p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Lee, Eric. "Un Ernst Jünger apaciguado." T. 3p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Loos, Paul Arthur. "Ernst Jünger." Radio text, dated July 21, 1949. T.cc. 4p., 1949 July 21 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Möller-Witten, Hans. "'Was wäre, wenn --?" T. with numerous h. corr. (by Paetel). 2p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Nebel, Gerhard. "Versuch über Ernst Jünger, aus 'Feuer und Wasser'." T. 32p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Niekisch, Ernst. "Waldgang." Contains notes: "Abschrift, Dezember 1951. Unveröffentlicht." T.cc. 5p., Undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Regensburger, Marianne. "Ernst Jünger." Dated January 1948. T.cc. 20p., 1948 January (Box 38, Folder 11)